I tell you something, Carter.
If I didn't have white hair
before this case, it's getting there now.
Every time we think we got something,
it slips right through our fingers.
But I really don't think the boy did it.
I'll tell you one thing, if I was keeping
a young, good-Iooking woman
and she started stepping out on me,
especially with a younger man,
I'd be madder than hell.
I don't know if I'd be mad enough
to kill her, but somebody was.
What do you think?
This is the lobby, Hobson speaking.
Get up to 1 1 02 right away.
There's a woman screaming for help.
Something terrible has happened.
Hurry.
That's it. Charlene.
- Charlene.
- What?
You've organised my desk again.
- Looking for these?
- Yeah, yeah.
I guess when you get a certain age,
that's it, huh?
Dad.
I've been going over our books.
- Good.
- We're doing very well.
- Do you want a raise?
- Nope.
- Vacation?
Remember telling me
about when you were a kid,
and that boy lost his overcoat?
- Yeah.
- And you gave him yours?
- Why don't we do that again?
Charlene, it's summertime.
What I'm trying to say is that
I think we should take a case
for nothing every now and then.
- We do.
- When?
Every now and then.
Dad, you've heard about this boy,
Kevin Meredith,
who was arrested
for killing his girlfriend?
- Yeah.
- I just had a long talk with his mother.
Charlene, the public defender's office
will do a fine job.
I used to be one of them.
I can speak for them.
He'll get a great defence.
His mom said he was advised
against even trying to go to college.
They said he wouldn't make it.
Well, he's been holding down two jobs
and he's an honour student.
She said she hoped it wasn't true,
but she heard the Matlock office
only worked for money.
She said he never owned
an overcoat.
So tell us what happened.
We'd been making love.
I went into the bathroom
to take a shower.
When I came out, there was a knife.
I picked it up...
...and Joanne was dead.
Did you see anybody?
Hear anybody?
- Anybody hate her?
- She was wonderful.
- Everybody liked her.
- Somebody didn't like her.
And right now,
the police and the DA think that's you.
I loved her.
I'm sorry, Kevin,
but that's not a defence.
Then what the hell is?
Did Joanne have some money?
I mean, judging from her address--
Her family was rich. Why?
Did she help you out now and then?
I never took anything from her.
She was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I loved her.
And if you think anything else,
you can just get out of here.
Well, that's some temper
you got there.
I hope it won't be the death of you.
Joanne believed in me.
She believed I was gonna make it.
Be somebody.
That's part of why
I loved her so much.
She believed in me
when nobody else did.
She believed in me.
Well, come on, son.
Your arraignment's in half an hour.
Well, good morning, Lloyd.
How's everything in your life?
Morning, Ben.
You are always up, aren't you?
Well, I'm in a trade I like,
and I got another winner.
- Are your clients ever guilty?
- Not if I can help it.
Superior Court 3 is now in session.
The Honourable Judge Carter Addison
presiding. All rise.
We'll start with
the private counsel cases.
The State v. Meredith.
Benjamin Matlock for the defence,
Your Honour.
Defendant has been advised
of his rights,
waives reading of the indictment,
pleads not guilty, requests a jury trial.
Time is waived.
How would September 28th,
9 a.m. be, counsellor?
Fine with me, Your Honour.
Agreed.
Oh, Mr. Matlock,
I'd like to see you in chambers
when I'm finished here.
Of course.
Thank you so much
for defending my son.
We'll give it our best shot.
I know.
Phil, I know,
but the cat is now out of the bag.
Wha--? All right, look,
so it's not a surprise.
I'll tell you what, I'll act surprised.
All evening, I promise.
All right, I'll see you then.
I'm sorry, Ben. Some of the boys
were gonna surprise me
with a party at the Windsor,
celebrating my tenth year
on the bench.
My clerk just let it slip.
Ten years? Has it been that long?
As of tomorrow.
- Boy, the years go by.
- Too fast.
I remember when
we both had brown hair.
Oh, yes, right, well...
The old law society picture
from school.
- I remember a lot of those guys.
- You never did join, did you?
No, I never was much of a joiner.
I remember you were a hard worker.
Didn't you--? Weren't you
holding down a couple of jobs?
Well, it was either hold down
a couple of jobs or not go to school.
I always admired you, Ben.
- Yeah? I never knew that.
- Sit down.
I wanted to talk to you--
- Off the record.
- Yeah.
You know Paul Devereau's boy,
Dale,
passed the bar last year, and naturally,
Paul's gonna take him into the firm.
Oh, I'm a strong believer in nepotism.
So is my daughter, Charlene.
Well, anyway, Dale doesn't have
a lot of courtroom experience,
and it occurred to me this Meredith
case might be good practise for him.
Well, he's very bright.
I mean, he'll do a good job.
You're asking me to step aside?
Well, just to help Paul's boy out.
Well, Carter...
...I feel I have an obligation here.
I know it would be good practise
for Paul's boy,
but I've already accepted the case.
I know Paul's boy would do a good job,
but l-- I just--
I feel like I should stay on.
Well, it was just a thought.
Sure, sure.
Hey, listen, happy tenth.
Thank you.
It's strange. It's very strange.
I mean, if it had happened
on the street it would be strange,
but in his chambers,
it's very strange.
You're talking to yourself again.
Get this.
Carter Addison
calls me into his office
and asks me to step aside
on the Meredith case
and give it to Paul Devereau's boy.
- Dale.
- Yeah.
- Dale?
- Isn't that strange?
Never heard of a judge
doing anything like that.
- Hello, people.
- Hey, Tyler.
Tyler, I've been looking for you
all morning.
Well, I've been busy
getting my fall wardrobe together.
You just got a new wardrobe.
A man in my position cannot afford
to be five minutes out of style.
What position is that?
I have been nominated Young Atlanta
Businessman of the Year.
- Who nominated you?
- Me.
- You?
- Yeah.
And it's within the rules.
And if I win, the local financial
community will open its doors
and its chequebooks to me.
- What's the case?
- Kevin Meredith, pro bono.
There's no fee?
Well, look at the publicity.
Young Atlanta Businessman
of the Year with a heart of gold.
Anyone ever tell you
that you are one--
Absolutely.
- Coming?
- Wouldn't miss it.
- Tyler.
- Lieutenant.
- Hello, Ben.
- Hello, Rupert.
- Charlene. We about done here, Ben.
- Oh, good.
You wanna visit
with the building manager?
Don't you trust our lab, Ben?
Well, they're good, they're just
not looking to help Kevin Meredith.
Hey, Tyler.
There's no fingerprints in the bedroom
to speak of.
- They're all smudged.
- Look at that.
A burned spot.
Look at that ashtray.
Isn't that a pipe-smoker's ashtray?
Yeah, you can see where the bowl
fits right in there and there.
Check that for prints, huh?
Look around and see
if you can find some tobacco.
There's a cognac bottle in the kitchen,
see if it's got any prints.
You got it.
Dad. Building manager
was reasonably cooperative.
Now, he said Joanne Leigh
lived here for six months.
Paid for the whole year in advance.
Thirty-two thousand dollars.
Now, I'm wondering how a student
could afford $32,000.
Kevin said her people have money.
Manager told me
her mother's been calling in here.
Wanted to get Joanne's car
so she could sell it.
- Sell it?
- She lives over in Hastings.
She works as a chambermaid
in a hotel.
He said she's the only family
Joanne had.
He also told me that
when Joanne first moved in here,
she got two sets of keys.
Then about two months ago,
about the same time
she started seeing Kevin,
she asked for another set of keys.
So if Kevin Meredith didn't kill her,
then somebody came in
while he was taking a shower and did.
It may be whoever
got that other set of keys.
You know,
I can't get over Carter Addison
asking me to step aside on this.
I mean, I can understand a lawyer
asking a judge to step aside
because of a prejudice,
but a judge asking a lawyer,
don't you think that's odd?
Yeah, it is.
Ben, I didn't find any fingerprints
on that cognac bottle.
I did find this.
A pipe cleaner and some tobacco.
Oh, no.
This city kills me.
Here's a street
where absolutely nothing's happening
and you can only park here
for an hour.
I told you to read the signs.
How many parking spaces
did Joanne Leigh have?
She was assigned two,
but there was construction
going on in the garage,
so she was down to one.
So whoever was visiting her
had to park on the street.
Kevin Meredith doesn't have a car.
Check all the parking tickets issued
around here
in last two or three months.
- Parking tickets?
- Yeah.
- All of them?
If somebody was keeping Joanne Leigh
and didn't wanna be seen,
he might have been parking around
here, and like somebody I know,
gotten a lot of tickets.
Hey, Ben, you got any idea
how long that's gonna take?
For the Young Businessman
of the Year, probably a heartbeat.
Wanna drive over to Hastings
and visit the girl's mama?
Yeah.
- You drive.
- Why?
Because I'm the senior partner
and I just got a ticket and everything.
Keep your eyes on the road,
stay in the speed limit,
and no rock 'n' roll on the radio.
I'm taking you back to the office.
I don't think you understand my anger,
how I feel, or anything at all.
Well, I'm sure you've had
a terrible loss, Mrs. Leigh.
My loss happened a long time ago.
You mean when your daughter
left home?
I was glad she wanted
to go to school.
First she'd come home on vacations
and then she stopped
coming home at all.
She'd go home with her friends.
She never liked it here in Hastings.
Hated it, so she left.
Can I sell her car?
I'll see what I can do.
We'll need you to testify at the trial.
You're working for the boy
who killed her.
We think somebody else
may have done that, Mrs. Leigh.
It seems that there was someone else
in Joanne's life.
Oh, you mean the man
who was keeping her.
- Did she say who it was?
- No, no, and I never asked.
All I know is that
he was some sort of bigshot.
He paid for her school.
We'd like you to tell the court
about this.
- You mean go to Atlanta?
- That's right.
Well, maybe. Maybe I could do that.
I got expenses if I do.
Travel, a place to stay.
How much?
Five.
Five thousand.
It's not our policy to pay people
for telling the truth, Mrs. Leigh.
I'm sorry.
This is your subpoena.
Requires your presence in court.
- Hi, Ben.
- Oh, hi.
- What do you make of her?
- She's tough.
I think she was really hurt
when her daughter left her.
Yes, Sarah. Okay.
- For you on one.
- I'll take it in the office.
Ben, I went through
all the parking tickets
for Joanne Leigh's neighbourhood.
I got a couple singles, a few doubles,
but nobody had a lot of parking tickets.
Nobody, huh?
And you were wrong about it
taking me a heartbeat.
It took me a lot of heartbeats.
Well, whoever was keeping her
had to park on the street,
and he had to have gotten
some parking tickets.
Well, I don't know what to tell you.
You know...
...if a person's got the juice...
...he could fix a ticket
and make it disappear
as though it never existed.
Did you know that?
Yeah, I knew that.
I don't know the details about how to--
Come on, fellas,
we haven't got much time.
Evening, Carter.
Well, hello, Ben.
What are you doing here?
Oh, sometimes I get the wanderlust.
Buy you a drink.
- Well, it's a little late.
- Oh, just one.
They got something here
very special.
Two Langlois Napoleon cognacs.
- Well, let me say good night.
- Yeah, okay.
Well, here's to dandelion season
or whatever season it is.
Yeah, I used to come here a lot.
They used to have jazz in here.
Yeah.
Remember those great dance bands
used to come through
and play dances at school?
Remember the name of that one
small band with the funny name?
''Snooky'' something?
Snooky Sandwich
and the Slippery Seven.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- You used to be a good dancer.
- I did okay.
- You still step out once in a while?
- Once in a while.
Good, huh?
Interestingly enough, I found a bottle
of this in Joanne Leigh's apartment.
- Who?
- Joanne Leigh, that murdered girl.
Oh, yes, yes.
I really am glad
I didn't step aside on this case.
It's fascinating. It really is.
There's a lot I don't know,
but I got a lot of things I think.
I think she was being kept
by an older man.
I think he smoked a pipe
and drank this same cognac.
I don't know that he killed her,
but he could have.
Felt threatened over her relationship
with this Kevin Meredith.
We're checking parking tickets
around her building,
around 23rd and Highview.
In fact, I got one there myself.
- You did?
- I don't suppose you could fix it?
- Well, I think not, Ben.
- I'm just joshing you.
Well, I better get home.
My wife's by herself.
- Big day tomorrow.
- For me too, Carter, for me too.
- Thanks, Ben. Good night.
- Yeah.
- Anything?
- Nothing good.
- No blood?
- No blood.
Damn. I thought we were
gonna get him tonight.
Well, it's not strange
that Carter Addison
asked you to step aside anymore,
is it?
No. Tell you one thing, he thinks
he's covered his tracks pretty good.
He's as cool as the centre seed
of a cucumber.
Ben, the judge's tobacco
from the restaurant
matches the blend I found
in Joanne's apartment.
Good.
- No blood in the car, huh?
- No blood.
Well, maybe he cleaned up
before he left.
Cleaned up? Where?
I don't know.
But he would have had to have done it
before he even got in his car.
You know...
...there's an apartment building
that's just across the street
from Joanne's,
and maybe when he first suspicioned
that she was stepping out on him--
Or that is, having somebody in.
--he might have gotten
the use of a place there.
Well, that would explain
why the parking tickets stopped.
The police said her shutters
were open.
Oh, Dad. You mean he got a place
in that building
so he could watch Kevin and Joanne
make love, maybe for weeks?
Well, let's just say
that maybe he was checking to see
if what he thought was happening
was happening.
- We better find it.
- Find what?
The apartment he was using,
if there was one.
Ben, there's probably
50 or 60 apartments
with a view of Joanne's windows.
Now, you can bet Addison
didn't use his real name.
Maybe he didn't even
rent the place himself.
Were you at your security desk
when the phone call came in?
Yes, sir, I was.
To the best of your recollection,
could you tell the court
what the man said?
I believe he said,
''Get up 1 1 02 right away.
A woman's screaming for help.
Something terrible is happening.''
What did you do?
Well, I got up there right away
and rang the bell.
When no one answered,
I let myself in.
- Was anyone there?
- Joanne's young friend.
I call your attention
to People's Exhibit 3.
Do you recognise it?
Yes, he was holding it
when I came in.
- Was anyone else in the apartment?
- No, sir, just him.
And is that man
presently in the courtroom?
Yes, sir, he is.
Would you identify him?
He's right over there.
Let the record show that the witness
identified the defendant.
No further questions.
Any cross-examination?
Mr. Hobson.
How long have you worked
at your apartment building?
Ten years, since the day
they opened the doors.
You know all the tenants?
Every last one of them,
down to the kids and the dogs.
And the dogs.
- I bet they know you.
- Yes, sir, they do.
You know,
something seems strange to me.
You testified that a man phoned you
and said, ''Get up to 1 1 02 right away.''
But he didn't call you by your name.
He didn't say,
''Harry, get up to 1 1 02,'' did he?
No, he didn't.
- Harry is your first name, isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
- Did you recognise the man's voice?
- No, I didn't.
Mr. Hobson, are there house phones
in your building?
Yes, sir, there are.
- There one on every floor?
- That's right.
So someone could have called
from a house phone
rather than one of the apartments.
- Isn't that correct?
- Objection.
Relevancy.
Your Honour, I'm attempting to show
that to call the security guard,
a person does not necessarily
have to be a tenant.
Anyone could have come in
off the street and done it.
Sustained.
But, Your Honour,
if someone other than Kevin Meredith
killed Joanne Leigh,
then that person could have used
the house phone in the hall.
Mr. Matlock,
don't make me repeat myself.
The objection is sustained.
Your Honour,
may I approach the bench?
Counsel.
Your Honour,
defence is attempting to show
that someone else
had access to the dead woman's
apartment, and that phone.
Counsellor for the defence is indulging
in totally unjustified speculation.
This is a capital crime,
and I ask for the widest possible
latitude for my client.
Mr. Matlock, you've made your point.
Now, I will say, for the last time,
you will confine your examination
to the issues at hand.
Now, may we get on with this,
please?
Something else, Counsellor?
No.
Not yet.
- Is defence ready to proceed?
- Yes, Your Honour.
I call Claire Leigh to the stand.
Is Claire Leigh present?
Your Honour, this witness
may not have answered our subpoena.
May we take a brief recess
while we try to learn of her intentions?
Court is recessed for 30 minutes.
We haven't met.
I'm Joanne Leigh's mother.
They're waiting for you in court,
Mrs. Leigh.
Well, I thought we should talk first.
- Why is that?
- Joanne told me all about you.
That's not possible.
I didn't know your daughter.
Look, you know I don't have time
to play games here.
In a few minutes,
I'm gonna be on that stand,
and I know plenty
about you and Joanne.
But I'll keep my mouth shut
if you make it worth my while.
If you think I'm bluffing,
you're gonna be real sorry.
Real sorry.
Okay.
Wait, wait.
Mrs. Leigh.
You were Joanne's mother.
Yes.
And you're a woman
of modest means.
I worked hard all my life.
But your daughter lived very well
here in Atlanta.
She had a wonderful apartment
and lots of pretty clothes.
I was real proud of how well
my Joanne had done for herself.
Would you explain to the court
how a student with no family support
could afford all this luxury?
Well, she worked for it, of course.
- How did she support herself?
- As a model.
She was very beautiful.
I have scrapbooks
full of her pictures at home.
But modelling wasn't
the only way she got money, was it?
Yes.
Far as I know.
Are you telling this court
that your daughter paid for this luxury
apartment herself by modelling?
- Yes.
- Mrs. Leigh, you're under oath.
Objection. Counsel is harassing
his own witness.
Sustained.
Your Honour, I'm allowed to examine
my own witness any way I choose,
especially if I'm surprised
by her testimony,
and right now I can guarantee you
I'm flabbergasted by it.
Mr. Matlock, may I remind you
that in this courtroom
you may not harass a witness
under any circumstances.
Now, you may proceed.
I urge you to use caution and restraint.
Thank you for your advice,
Your Honour.
Mrs. Leigh.
Do you recall having a conversation
with my daughter a few days ago?
Yes, I do.
Do you recall stating then
that your daughter was being kept
by a powerful man?
No.
Isn't it true you said this man
made it possible for your daughter
to live very well?
You're trying to trick me.
And didn't you say this same man
made it possible for your daughter
- to come to school in Atlanta?
- Why are you telling these lies?
My baby would never take money
from a man like that.
She was a sweet, wonderful girl.
And now she's dead,
and I know who killed her. He did.
She told me.
She was scared to death
of his temper.
She said she was trying
to break it off,
and he threatened her,
and now she's dead.
He is the one who killed her.
No further questions.
Court is adjourned
until tomorrow morning, 9 a.m.
All rise.
Is counsel ready?
Your Honour,
may I approach the bench?
- What is it, Mr. Matlock?
- I'll get right to it, Your Honour.
Defence intends to call His Honour
as its next witness.
I have no information
relevant to this case.
Mr. Matlock, do you realise
the implication of your intention?
I'm afraid I do, Your Honour,
but I have an obligation
to present evidence
that I believe will be helpful
to my client's defence.
I think this is a complete waste of the
court's time and the state's money.
Your Honour's testifying
could mean a mistrial.
Then we'd have to start
this whole trial all over again.
That doesn't make any sense.
I have a sincere belief
that Your Honour
may have knowledge of facts
that may shed some light on this case.
My duty is to Mr. Meredith,
not to the state treasury.
I'll see both counsel
and the court reporter in chambers.
And I don't believe that I have
any information to help your client,
but I understand your position,
and we all appreciate
what a mistrial will cost us
in terms of time and money.
Now, Judge Cooksey is available.
If you and Mr. Burgess
will agree to Judge Cooksey
presiding over my examination,
I think we can put this matter to rest,
Mr. Matlock.
If you can show
that I know something important here,
then I'll agree to step down
and a mistrial will be declared.
If you can't, then I will retake
the bench tomorrow morning,
we'll finish this case
and send it to the jury.
Mr. Burgess?
It's unusual, but the state agrees
if Mr. Matlock does.
Defence goes along
with your proposal.
All rise.
Your Honour,
defence has just been presented
with new evidence
that's important to our case.
May we take a brief recess
to prepare for our next witness?
All right. This court will recess
until 2:30 this afternoon.
The truth, the whole truth, and nothing
but the truth, so help me God.
Please be seated.
Mr. Addison.
Do you know Mrs. Claire Leigh?
Are you referring
to defence's witness?
- Yes, I am.
- I don't know her personally, no.
You are aware that she is the mother
of the deceased, Joanne Leigh?
I believe that was her testimony.
Have you had any occasion
to discuss this case with Mrs. Leigh?
Absolutely not.
Isn't it true that you met with her
this morning
- after she testified in your court?
- No, I did not.
And at that time,
didn't you give her an envelope
containing $1 5,000?
Objection.
The witness already testified
he never met with the woman.
Sustained.
Did you know Joanne Leigh?
- No.
- Never met her?
No.
Mr. Addison,
let me ask your opinion here.
If there were a condominium,
and its ownership were in question--
That is, it were in a lawsuit.
--could that condominium
be impounded by the court?
Yes.
So that neither party involved in that
lawsuit could enter that condominium?
Yes.
Now, if this condominium
were impounded by the court,
would it be difficult
for someone in the court,
say, a judge like yourself,
to obtain a key
to that impounded condominium?
This is getting a little hypothetical
for me, Mr. Matlock.
Is counsel about to come to a point?
Well, Your Honour,
I'm just trying to establish
that it would not be difficult.
In fact, it would be quite simple
for a judge to obtain a key
to an impounded condominium.
Now,
are you familiar with a condominium
building at 437 Highview Street?
No, I am not.
Let me refresh
Your Honour's memory.
This condominium building
is directly across from the apartment
building where Joanne Leigh lived.
Mr. Matlock, I have already stated
I am not familiar with this building.
Now, I agreed to testify
based on your assurances
that I would be a material witness.
So far,
you have demonstrated nothing.
Maybe this might clarify it.
From this condominium building,
with a pair of binoculars,
a person can look right into
Joanne Leigh's apartment,
which is what the killer did
while he watched and waited
for his chance to murder her.
Would Mr. William Bryan
please rise.
Now, this condominium building
is occupied
primarily by retired people.
Mr. Bryan is a former member
of the Atlanta police department.
- Do you recognise him?
- No, I do not.
You didn't see Mr. Bryan there
this morning
when you were in that building?
I have--
I've never been in that building.
I suppose we could have
Mr. Bryan testify
that he saw you in that building,
but then, that wouldn't prove
that you killed Joanne Leigh, would it?
Order. Order in the court.
Matlock, I warn you,
making these unsubstantiated charges
is contemptible.
Mr. Addison, I don't make
unsubstantiated charges.
You see, this morning...
...when you went back
to that condominium...
...when Mr. Bryan saw you,
to remove your clothes
that you had left there
till this whole thing was over...
...you didn't remove your clothes.
They were replacements
that were placed there
by my associate, Mr. Tyler Hudson.
These are your clothes.
This is your raincoat.
See Joanne Leigh's blood?
These are your gloves.
Your hat.
Your shoes.
Which I place into evidence now.
Carter.
You were one of the best
and one of the brightest.
I'm truly sorry it's come to this.
No further questions.
Your Honour, rather than a mistrial,
prosecution moves for dismissal.
Case dismissed.
- Good to hear.
- All right.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, sir.
- Ben, congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
Good job.
We can't thank you enough.
If you wanna thank someone,
thank her.
Your daughter would be very proud.
www.tvsubtitles.net